<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chris Gallo | Learn on Chris Gallo | Home</title>
    <link>https://hotdogsandeggs.com/learn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chris Gallo | Learn on Chris Gallo | Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hotdogsandeggs.com/learn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>08: Flexible Thinking</title>
      <link>https://hotdogsandeggs.com/learn/08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hotdogsandeggs.com/learn/08/</guid>
      <description>08: Flexible Thinking Biggest takeaway this week was try to be flexible in your thinking.
 be comfortable with uncertainty be observant, pay attention to what people do not say pay attention to actions, not just facts and numbers get to the truth, don&amp;rsquo;t always to try to organize it unlearn things, ask why  Consuming Thinking in Bets
FinishedThinking in Bets by Annie Duke.
This book teaches us that life is poker not chess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>07: How not what</title>
      <link>https://hotdogsandeggs.com/learn/07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hotdogsandeggs.com/learn/07/</guid>
      <description>07: How not what Biggest takeaway this week was how &amp;gt; what. In order to reshape your thinking habits, try the following:
 be the best credit-giver be the best mistake-admitter be the best finder of mistakes in good-outcomes  Consuming Thinking in Bets
Check out Thinking in Bets by Annie Duke and started to read this weekend.
Notes and excerpts:
Poker not chess. Life is more like poker, skill and luck.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>06: Move on</title>
      <link>https://hotdogsandeggs.com/learn/06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hotdogsandeggs.com/learn/06/</guid>
      <description>06: Move on Biggest takeaway this week was remember to move on. Don&amp;rsquo;t stay mad. Drive forward. Shit happens. Keep on keeping on.
Consuming More Scorecast
Finished reading Scorecasting by Tobias J. Moskowitz and L. Jon Wertheim this week.
Continuation of notes below:
Chapter 7: Rounding first: people have a bias to round numbers. It&amp;rsquo;s why more batters hit .300 than .299.
A batter is close to .300 at end of season?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>05: Value of the Act</title>
      <link>https://hotdogsandeggs.com/learn/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hotdogsandeggs.com/learn/05/</guid>
      <description>05: Value of the Act Value was a theme this week in what I read or consumed. Not all stats are created equal. Value in the act, not the act itself. It was a challenge to deal with uncertainity this week too.
Consuming Scorecast
Checked out Scorecasting by Tobias J. Moskowitz and L. Jon Wertheim from the library.
Started reading this week, notes below:
Notes or ideas/passages that stuck out to me:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>04: Be honest</title>
      <link>https://hotdogsandeggs.com/learn/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hotdogsandeggs.com/learn/04/</guid>
      <description>04: Be honest Biggest learning this week is to be honest. If you&amp;rsquo;re anxious, admit it. Say it out loud. You&amp;rsquo;ll feel better. Just be yourself.
Consuming The Numbers Game
Checked out The Numbers Game by Chris Andersen and David Sally from the library. This was an easy read for me.
The notes outlined in this post are a good summary.
Notes or ideas/passages that stuck out to me:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03: Slow down</title>
      <link>https://hotdogsandeggs.com/learn/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hotdogsandeggs.com/learn/03/</guid>
      <description>03: Slow down Biggest learning this week was to remember to slow down. Time moves faster as you get older, just slow down.
Consuming Sivers book notes: Courage to be disliked
Ton of tidbits from Ichiro Kishimi and Fumitake Koga&amp;rsquo;s book, Sivers notes are great.
Notes that stood out with my own perspective:
Meaning to experiences: we are not determined by our experiences, but by the meaning we give them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02: Non-zero system</title>
      <link>https://hotdogsandeggs.com/learn/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hotdogsandeggs.com/learn/02/</guid>
      <description>01: A Non-zero system Biggest learning this week was to develop a non-zero system. 1 &amp;gt; 0. Remember that.
Consuming Comment from reddit
This is maybe best reddit comment I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read. It comes from ryans01.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a summary of the 4 rules in my own words:
Rule 1: be consistent, one is better than zero. Do at least something that can help you toward your goal or dream each day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>01: Fast and Curious</title>
      <link>https://hotdogsandeggs.com/learn/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hotdogsandeggs.com/learn/01/</guid>
      <description>01: Fast and Curious Fast and curious. I thought this would be a fun name for a blog or newsletter for some reason. It&amp;rsquo;s silly.
But also a good a way to try to explain what I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to accomplish with this exercise. The goal is to write down or publish what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned to help me retain it and motivate me to keep learning new things.
It&amp;rsquo;s total stream of consciousness based off what I consumed and created during the past week or so.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>